export const chapter = "Chapter - 16: Chhatrapati Shivaji ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Who raised Shivaji spiritually and taught him to chant the Lord's name?",
        optionA: "His father",
        optionB: "His mother, Queen Jijabai",
        optionC: "His guru, Samarth Ramdas Swami",
        correctAnswer: "His mother, Queen Jijabai",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Shivaji led the Marathas against the oppressive rule of which group?",
        optionA: "British",
        optionB: "Mughals",
        optionC: "Portuguese",
        correctAnswer: "Mughals",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What did Shivaji do when he heard a calling for alms that he recognized as his Guru's voice?",
        optionA: "Ignored it",
        optionB: "Rushed to greet his Guru",
        optionC: "Sent a servant to check",
        correctAnswer: "Rushed to greet his Guru",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What did Shivaji offer to his Guru, Samarth Ramdas Swami, in a letter?",
        optionA: "His entire kingdom",
        optionB: "A royal meal",
        optionC: "A piece of land",
        correctAnswer: "His entire kingdom",
      },
      {
        question:
          "After offering his kingdom, what did Shivaji say he would do?",
        optionA: "Rule the kingdom with his Guru's guidance",
        optionB: "Serve his Guru at his feet",
        optionC: "Continue ruling as king",
        correctAnswer: "Serve his Guru at his feet",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What did Shivaji do when he was asked to follow his Guru and ask for alms?",
        optionA: "Refused to go",
        optionB: "Joined the group asking for alms",
        optionC: "Sent his servants instead",
        correctAnswer: "Joined the group asking for alms",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What did Samarth Ramdas Swami appoint Shivaji as, after he offered his kingdom?",
        optionA: "A minister",
        optionB: "A priest",
        optionC: "His representative to rule the kingdom in God's Name",
        correctAnswer: "His representative to rule the kingdom in God's Name",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How did Shivaji rule the kingdom after becoming Samarth Ramdas Swami's representative?",
        optionA: "He ruled it with cruelty and oppression",
        optionB: "He ruled it righteously, in the Name of God",
        optionC: "He continued to rule it as his own kingdom",
        correctAnswer: "He ruled it righteously, in the Name of God",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What does the story show about Shivaji's relationship with God and his Guru?",
        optionA: "He was indifferent to his Guru's teachings",
        optionB: "He easily offered his kingdom at the Guru's feet",
        optionC: "He never followed his Guru's guidance",
        correctAnswer: "He easily offered his kingdom at the Guru's feet",
      },
      {
        question:
          "According to the text, what should an ideal ruler do for the good of the people?",
        optionA: "Rule the kingdom with cruelty and oppression",
        optionB: "Lead by example and rule the kingdom as God's kingdom",
        optionC: "Focus on personal gain and power",
        correctAnswer: "Lead by example and rule the kingdom as God's kingdom",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "In the 17th century, Shivaji lived in the western part of India, in the state of _________.",
        options: ["Maharashtra", "Rajasthan", "Punjab"],
        correctAnswer: "Maharashtra",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Shivaji's mother, Queen Jijabai, raised him spiritually, teaching him to chant the ________ name when he was just a child.",
        options: ["King's", "Lord's", "Guru's"],
        correctAnswer: "Lord's",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Shivaji courageously led the Marathas against the oppressive rule of the ________.",
        options: ["British", "Mughals", "Persians"],
        correctAnswer: "Mughals",
      },
      {
        question:
          "One day, while attending to some royal matters, Shivaji heard a calling for alms and immediately recognized the voice as that of his Guru, ________ Swami.",
        options: ["Sant", "Ramdas", "Raman"],
        correctAnswer: "Ramdas",
      },
      {
        question:
          "After they were seated and fed a royal meal, Shivaji wrote something on a piece of paper and offered it to ________.",
        options: ["His mother", "His Guru", "His minister"],
        correctAnswer: "His Guru",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Swamiji told a devotee to open the letter and read it out loud. The letter was Shivaji's ________.",
        options: ["Recipe", "Wish", "Will"],
        correctAnswer: "Will",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Swamiji asked Shivaji, 'If you offer me all this, even the kingdom, then what will you do?' The king replied, 'I will offer myself completely to serve you, at your ________.'",
        options: ["Feet", "Palace", "Kingdom"],
        correctAnswer: "Feet",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Swamiji appointed Shivaji as his representative to rule the kingdom in ________ Name.",
        options: ["His", "God's", "Shivaji's"],
        correctAnswer: "God's",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Obediently, the disciple Shivaji returned to his Guru's palace and ruled the Guru's kingdom as his representative and by his Guru's ________, he ruled it righteously, in the Name of God.",
        options: ["Blessings", "Guidance", "Orders"],
        correctAnswer: "Guidance",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The story shows that an ideal ruler would lead by example and rule the kingdom as ________ for the good of the people.",
        options: ["A monarchy", "God's kingdom", "A democracy"],
        correctAnswer: "God's kingdom",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Safety rules are unimportant for us.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "To maintain good health, we must follow healthy habits in our routine.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Physical exercise and activity are not key factors for good health.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "One of the 'Do's mentioned in the text is to brush your teeth twice a day.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "It's unnecessary to take a bath regularly for good health.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Washing your hands after using the toilet is recommended for maintaining cleanliness.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Wearing neat and clean clothes is not important for health.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A balanced diet, including fruits and green vegetables, is crucial for good health.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "It's acceptable to eat stale food and food that is kept in the open for good health.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Chewing your food well is not a good eating practice for digestion.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
